<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on Dan [the] Salmon</title>
    <link>https://danthesalmon.com/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on Dan [the] Salmon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danthesalmon.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UFW, Docker, and Tailscale: Lessons Learned</title>
      <link>https://danthesalmon.com/ufw-docker-tailscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danthesalmon.com/ufw-docker-tailscale/</guid>
      <description>This is a cautionary tale about something that happened to me in the past few weeks. I&amp;rsquo;m posting it because I believe a lot can be learned by professionals (and others such as me) posting their security fails and problem-solving processes.
I have a server at Hetzner for a personal project. It&amp;rsquo;s running Ubuntu with Docker and there are a few Docker containers running, Postgres and RabbitMQ among them. Last week I logged into the server to do some work and noticed it was running a bit slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security Summit 2018 Highlights</title>
      <link>https://danthesalmon.com/cyber-security-summit-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danthesalmon.com/cyber-security-summit-2018/</guid>
      <description>I was fortunate enough to attend the 2018 Cyber Security Summit in Minneapolis, MN. Here I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to summarize each talk I attended into a small, digestible format, mostly written in their voices.
Student Breakfast By: Ryan Aniol - State of Minnesota
This was a super informative informal breakfast hosted by Ryan who aimed the talk at the students like myself. It was really nice to hear information directly relevant to my situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiFi Security Testing Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://danthesalmon.com/wifi-security-testing-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 16:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danthesalmon.com/wifi-security-testing-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Prepare Wireless Card View Network Cards: iwconfig Kill Wireless Processes: airmon-ng check kill View Networks airodump-ng wlan0 Capture traffic airodump-ng --bssid 04:A1:51:9F:98:BB --wps --write ISSO-WPA2 --channel 6 wlan0 where:
--bssid - MAC of router --wps - Output WPS information, may be able to try Reaver --write - File name to write to. No extension --channel - Statically set a channel. Don&#39;t need to unless de-authing wlan0 - Wireless interface	Deauth - Do while capturing aireplay-ng --deauth 0 -a 04:A1:51:9F:11:11 -c E0:AC:CB:DA:1B:1B wlan0 where:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I switched from Android to iOS</title>
      <link>https://danthesalmon.com/why-i-switched-from-android-to-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danthesalmon.com/why-i-switched-from-android-to-ios/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article is not just a stringent comparison of Apple vs Android, but a look at the whole picture that I took while deciding which phone to switch to.
A few months ago, my beloved Verizon HTC One M8 began to lose it’s charge at an alarming rate. It would be at 40% battery by lunch time after a day of very moderate use. Luckily, I was due for an upgrade from Verizon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
