<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dan [the] Salmon</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/</link><description>Recent content on Dan [the] Salmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danthesalmon.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A New Proxmox Server</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/new-proxmox-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/new-proxmox-server/</guid><description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about previously, all compute workloads in my homelab are run on an older HP Z620 workstation. This machine runs everything I need it to without complaint and has done so for years. Recently I started thinking more about replacing it, or at least transplanting its components into something I can rackmount. I don&amp;rsquo;t like that it&amp;rsquo;s the only piece of homelab gear that doesn&amp;rsquo;t reside neatly in the 18U rack.</description></item><item><title>S3Scanner featured in Metasploit, 2nd Edition</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/s3scanner-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/s3scanner-book/</guid><description>S3Scanner gains a glowing recommendation</description></item><item><title>2025 Projects</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/2025-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/2025-projects/</guid><description>Time to put up or shut up</description></item><item><title>Windows Kills SMB Speeds When Using Tailscale</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/windows-smb-tailscale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/windows-smb-tailscale/</guid><description>The Issue Yesterday when trying to transfer an ISO file from a TrueNAS SMB share, I was getting horrible transfer speeds.
The NAS can definitely saturate a gigabit link which is what my desktop connects to the switch over. I had seen this behavior before and had a feeling it was related to having Tailscale running - the last time it happened I quit Tailscale and my fast transfers returned.</description></item><item><title>Bookmark Batch 02</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/bookmark-batch-02/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/bookmark-batch-02/</guid><description>#FuckStalkerware pt. 3 - ownspy got, well, owned maia.crimew.gay article stalkerware web exploit Part 3 of a series of hacktivist posts examining stalkerware apps from the inside out. The Chronicles of a New York Locksmith | Keys to the City | The New Yorker Documentary www.youtube.com video documentary locksmith DEF CON 31 - The Art of Compromising C2 Servers A Web App Vulns Perspective - Vangelis Stykas www.youtube.com video C2 web exploit defcon Vangelis does a fantastic job walking through the exploitation of a half dozen malware C2 systems.</description></item><item><title>Cracking a Locked Apple Note</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/crack-apple-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/crack-apple-notes/</guid><description>There is a note in Apple Notes on my phone that I cannot open.
The note is not mission critical (gift ideas for my family members), but I would like to have access to it again. I created the note September 21, 2022 and at some point thought it would be funny to put an additional password on a note that contains such trivial information. Some time in the last 6 months, something changed with the note.</description></item><item><title>Bookmark Batch 01</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/bookmark-batch-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/bookmark-batch-01/</guid><description>Background This is a new thing I&amp;rsquo;m trying out - a list of links to articles, videos, podcasts or anything else that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across recently that I think are very interesting. I may add some context to them, but probably most will just be the link and some tags. Let me know if you find this sort of thing useful.
How to launder $600 million on the internet www.npr.org article finance crypto A Visual Journey Through Computer Setups Revealed by Recent Cybercrime Raids realhackhistory.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew is awesome</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/homebrew-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/homebrew-is-awesome/</guid><description>Contributing to Homebrew - so easy a caveman could do it</description></item><item><title>State of the Homelab: 2023</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/state-of-homelab-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/state-of-homelab-2023/</guid><description>I started my homelab almost 10 years ago. At that time my goal was to learn more about Linux, FreeBSD, and virtualization tools as well as having an &amp;ldquo;always-on&amp;rdquo; machine to do long-running tasks. This post is a snapshot of what the network looks like today as well as a little history behind the different parts.
Obligatory Diagram Here is a mostly complete picture of the homelab as it stands today</description></item><item><title>UFW, Docker, and Tailscale: Lessons Learned</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/ufw-docker-tailscale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/ufw-docker-tailscale/</guid><description>Learning new tech is hard.</description></item><item><title>Validating JSON Quickly with Go</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/validate-json-quickly-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/validate-json-quickly-go/</guid><description>How fast can we validate a large text file of JSON?</description></item><item><title>Running Docker on Proxmox</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/running-docker-on-proxmox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/running-docker-on-proxmox/</guid><description>There are a few different ways to run Docker on Proxmox. Here are some instructions and unscientific benchmarks comparing them.</description></item><item><title>Tumblr Has a Spam Problem</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/tumblr-has-a-spam-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/tumblr-has-a-spam-problem/</guid><description>I have an account on Tumblr, though I seem to be one of the few people still on the site. Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed an uptick in the amount of spam accounts following me. A considerable increase, in fact, so I decided to try to quantify how pervasive the problem was.
Searching for Spam The first thing I had to do was create some criteria to use for categorizing accounts as &amp;ldquo;spam&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sponsors</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/sponsors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 21:44:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/sponsors/</guid><description>In order to support this site, some ads may be posted from time to time. These ads will take the form of simple referral links to services I use.
While I respect the use of ad-blockers (and run them myself on all my browsers), I kindly ask that users do not add my site to any blocklists. Any ads that appear on this website will adhere to the following set of rules:</description></item><item><title>AttackDefense - Cracking Hashcat Guide</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/attackdefense-cracking-hashcat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 20:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/attackdefense-cracking-hashcat/</guid><description>AttackDefense is a new site with all sorts of awesome labs and CTFs for training. Best of all: the site is free.
In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll detail how to complete the &amp;amp;amp;ldquo;Cracking MD5 Hashes&amp;amp;amp;rdquo; lab, though this strategy should work for most labs in the &amp;ldquo;Hashcat All&amp;rdquo; section. If you are unfamiliar with Hashcat, I&amp;rsquo;d strongly recommend reading the wiki or following Youtube tutorials elsewhere before trying this challenge.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Security Summit 2018 Highlights</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/cyber-security-summit-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/cyber-security-summit-2018/</guid><description>I was fortunate enough to attend the 2018 Cyber Security Summit in Minneapolis, MN. Here I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to summarize each talk I attended into a small, digestible format, mostly written in their voices.
Student Breakfast By: Ryan Aniol - State of Minnesota
This was a super informative informal breakfast hosted by Ryan who aimed the talk at the students like myself. It was really nice to hear information directly relevant to my situation.</description></item><item><title>HackTheBox 'Poison' - Own User Guide</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/hackthebox-poison/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 04:33:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/hackthebox-poison/</guid><description>Note: If you are currently trying to get access to this box, I highly recommend you try it yourself first and only use this guide if you really are stuck. Intro Now that the Poison box is retired on hackthebox, we can talk publicly about how to gain access to this machine. While this machine was active, I only took the time to gain user access, not all the way to root.</description></item><item><title>Running Oracle 18c on MacOS</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/running-oracle-12c-on-macos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/running-oracle-12c-on-macos/</guid><description>Update: May 14, 2019 This article originally contained instructions for running Oracle 12c. The Docker image that was being used was deleted by the author and so was not usable. I have updated the instructions to work again, though the image it uses now runs Oracle 18c. If you need to run 12c specifically, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to look for instructions elsewhere. Some screenshots may now be out of date.
In this post, we will go through the steps of installing Oracle 12c in a Docker container and connect to the database using SQL Developer on a Mac.</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 21:44:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/search/</guid><description> Search Enter comma-separated search terms</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/contact/</guid><description> Twitter Github Keybase dan(at)salmon(dot)cat</description></item><item><title>Electroneum - First Impressions</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/first-impressions-of-electroneum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/first-impressions-of-electroneum/</guid><description>A coworker recently sent me a link to Yet Another Cryptocurrency. Like most people, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty burnt out with all these new coins and ICO&amp;rsquo;s popping up each week. In fact, I get about 5-10 ICO spam emails in my Junk mail folder.
This one looked to be just a little different, though. He was excited because this one allows you to use your phone to mine. I talked to him about how it&amp;rsquo;s a neat idea, but ultimately probably won&amp;rsquo;t be profitable, especially compare to a multi-GPU setup.</description></item><item><title>Moving ZFS datasets between volumes</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/moving-zfs-datasets-between-volumes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 03:07:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/moving-zfs-datasets-between-volumes/</guid><description>If you run ZFS like I do (and I think you should) there will probably come at time when you need to migrate a dataset from one volume to another. This was done in FreeNAS (FreeBSD), but the steps should apply to any *nix system with ZFS
The great thing about ZFS is that we can do most of this migration with our services and everything still running.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start by taking a snapshot of the dataset we want to move.</description></item><item><title>2017 Cyber Security Summit</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/2017-cyber-security-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 21:57:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/2017-cyber-security-summit/</guid><description>Student Breakfast - MN IT Services w/ Chris Buse $400M budget for MNIT 0% unemployment rate MNIT wants to train/develop IT skills. Everyones wants skilled people but no one wants to train Lots of operational jobs Looking for interns with lots of general skills Flexible hours/locations Q/A with Chris &amp;ldquo;Are certifications worth it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Focus on certs, even though I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re very useful. They&amp;rsquo;re mostly just to get passed HR.</description></item><item><title>WiFi Security Testing Cheatsheet</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/wifi-security-testing-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 16:38:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/wifi-security-testing-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Prepare Wireless Card View Network Cards: iwconfig Kill Wireless Processes: airmon-ng check kill View Networks airodump-ng wlan0 Capture traffic airodump-ng --bssid 04:A1:51:9F:98:BB --wps --write ISSO-WPA2 --channel 6 wlan0 where:
--bssid - MAC of router --wps - Output WPS information, may be able to try Reaver --write - File name to write to. No extension --channel - Statically set a channel. Don't need to unless de-authing wlan0 - Wireless interface Deauth - Do while capturing aireplay-ng --deauth 0 -a 04:A1:51:9F:11:11 -c E0:AC:CB:DA:1B:1B wlan0 where:</description></item><item><title>Why I switched from Android to iOS</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/why-i-switched-from-android-to-ios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/why-i-switched-from-android-to-ios/</guid><description>Note: This article is not just a stringent comparison of Apple vs Android, but a look at the whole picture that I took while deciding which phone to switch to.
A few months ago, my beloved Verizon HTC One M8 began to lose it’s charge at an alarming rate. It would be at 40% battery by lunch time after a day of very moderate use. Luckily, I was due for an upgrade from Verizon.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 21:44:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/about/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Dan. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in Information Security, Data Privacy, and Programming.
Projects S3scanner - Scan for open S3 buckets and dump contents miniprint - A medium interaction printer honeypot 🍯 venmo-data - A dataset of 7 million transactions scraped from the Venmo public API watchtower - PoC to detect and alert when Rogue AP and Deauth attacks occur Vulnerabilities CVE-2025-27422 - Authentication Bypass via User Creation (FACTION) Press You Should Really, Really Make All Your Venmo Transactions Private Madison Malone Kircher, New York Magazine, 2019 Millions of Venmo transactions scraped in warning over privacy settings Zack Whittaker, TechCrunch, 2019 Venmo Opens Your Transaction History To Anyone Who Wants To Look.</description></item><item><title>Allow a Chromecast through a WatchGuard firewall</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/allow-a-chromecast-through-a-watchguard-firewall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 21:44:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/allow-a-chromecast-through-a-watchguard-firewall/</guid><description>Background I recently picked up a Chromecast for my TV so I could stream Netflix easier since XBMC’s addon is terrible if you don’t want to use a keyboard. It was super easy to setup, but after it updated and connected to my WiFi I couldn’t see it from my phone. I did some digging and found that my WatchGuard 25W was the culprit. After I added an any-any rule I was able to see it, but that left it wide-open on my network.</description></item><item><title>Fix “Some settings are managed by your system administrator” in Windows 7</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/fix-some-settings-are-managed-by-your-system-administrator-in-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/fix-some-settings-are-managed-by-your-system-administrator-in-windows-7/</guid><description>Background A few months back, I was doing cleanup on a system that I had cleaned of malware. Whatever junk was on there had configured a local proxy server to run, but Malwarebytes had ripped it out. The system unfortunately still thought it was supposed to use the proxy server that doesn’t exist; consequently, I had no internet access. That’s an easy enough fix, right? I open Internet Options and change the LAN settings to not use a proxy and close it.</description></item><item><title>Change Network Location in Windows 8.1/2012 R2 from Powershell</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/change-network-location-in-windows-8-1-2012-r2-from-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 20:46:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/change-network-location-in-windows-8-1-2012-r2-from-powershell/</guid><description>Step 1 From an elevated PowerShell window issue the following command to gather some information about our current network profile:
Get-NetConnectionProfile Name : Unidentified Network InterfaceAlias : Ethernet InterfaceIndex : 10 NetworkCategory : Public IPv4Connectivity : LocalNetwork IPv6Connectivity : LocalNetwork The only information we really need from this output is the “InterfaceIndex”
Step 2 After getting the InterfaceIndex, we run the following command:
Set-NetConnectionProfile -InterfaceIndex 10 -NetworkCategory Private The last argument is what category you want to switch it to.</description></item><item><title>Fix HAXM Emulation Error in Android Studio</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/fix-haxm-emulation-error-in-android-studio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 04:57:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/fix-haxm-emulation-error-in-android-studio/</guid><description>Requirement Note: Android Studio requires an Intel processor with VT-X support for it’s built-in emulators to work. If you want to do Android development with emulators on an AMD processor, I would highly suggest using Genymotion. If you’re not sure if your Intel processor supports VT-X, Intel has an article here.
This error is occurring because Android Studio requires Intel Hardware Accelerated Execution Manager (Intel HAXM) to run it’s emulators. All we need to do is install this tool.</description></item><item><title>Fix Ruby on Rails Certificate Issue</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/fix-ruby-certificate-issue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 01:11:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/fix-ruby-certificate-issue/</guid><description>While attempting a “rails new” command, I was greeted with this lovely message:
An error occurred while installing rake (10.4.2), and Bundler cannot continue. So after doing some research, it turns out all you need to do is a Gem update:
gem update --system Unless of course, this results in this error like it did for me:
ERROR: While executing gem ... (Gem::RemoteFetcher::FetchError) SSL_connect returned=1 errno=0 state=SSLv3 read server certificate B: certificate verify failed (https://api.</description></item><item><title>View/Reset SickRage Web Password</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/view-reset-sickrage-web-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 03:56:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/view-reset-sickrage-web-password/</guid><description>Background I recently forgot my password for SickRage and was surprised by the little documentation online. I have it installed in a jail in FreeNAS, so that’s what I’ll be focused on here but the instructions should be exactly the same if you have it installed inside an OS.
Steps It’s actually really easy, assuming you have command-line access. In FreeNAS, open a shell on your SickRage jail and edit the following file:</description></item><item><title>Create a Seedbox Jail in FreeNAS with rTorrent / ruTorrent / lighttpd</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/create-seedbox-jail-freenas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 04:33:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/create-seedbox-jail-freenas/</guid><description>Intro / Credits After much work and starting from scratch a few times, I finally got a working jail put together that uses ruTorrent, rTorrent, and Lighttpd to create a very nice personal seedbox in FreeNAS. I should give a lot of credit to FlyingPersian and his thread on the FreeNAS forum for the great information. I’m going to shamelessly steal a lot of his guide but correct some things and add improvements that I found.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://danthesalmon.com/besside-ng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/besside-ng/</guid><description>Crack multiple networks simultaneiously with besside-ng and hashcat besside-ng wlan0 Let it run until it has many handshakes</description></item></channel></rss>