<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freenas on Dan [the] Salmon</title>
    <link>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/tags/freenas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freenas on Dan [the] Salmon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 03:07:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/tags/freenas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving ZFS datasets between volumes</title>
      <link>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/moving-zfs-datasets-between-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 03:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/moving-zfs-datasets-between-volumes/</guid>
      <description>If you run ZFS like I do (and I think you should) there will probably come at time when you need to migrate a dataset from one volume to another. This was done in FreeNAS (FreeBSD), but the steps should apply to any *nix system with ZFS
The great thing about ZFS is that we can do most of this migration with our services and everything still running.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start by taking a snapshot of the dataset we want to move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View/Reset SickRage Web Password</title>
      <link>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/view-reset-sickrage-web-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 03:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/view-reset-sickrage-web-password/</guid>
      <description>Background I recently forgot my password for SickRage and was surprised by the little documentation online. I have it installed in a jail in FreeNAS, so that’s what I’ll be focused on here but the instructions should be exactly the same if you have it installed inside an OS.
Steps It’s actually really easy, assuming you have command-line access. In FreeNAS, open a shell on your SickRage jail and edit the following file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Seedbox Jail in FreeNAS with rTorrent / ruTorrent / lighttpd</title>
      <link>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/create-seedbox-jail-freenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 04:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sa7mon.github.io/personal-site-hugo/create-seedbox-jail-freenas/</guid>
      <description>Intro / Credits After much work and starting from scratch a few times, I finally got a working jail put together that uses ruTorrent, rTorrent, and Lighttpd to create a very nice personal seedbox in FreeNAS. I should give a lot of credit to FlyingPersian and his thread on the FreeNAS forum for the great information. I’m going to shamelessly steal a lot of his guide but correct some things and add improvements that I found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>