<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android on Dan [the] Salmon</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in Android on Dan [the] Salmon</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 01:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danthesalmon.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I switched from Android to iOS</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/posts/why-i-switched-from-android-to-ios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/posts/why-i-switched-from-android-to-ios/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Note: This article is not just a stringent comparison of Apple vs Android, but a look at the whole picture that I took while deciding which phone to switch to.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months ago, my beloved Verizon HTC One M8 began to lose it’s charge at an alarming rate. It would be at 40% battery by lunch time after a day of very moderate use. Luckily, I was due for an upgrade from Verizon. This was great, but presented an issue: I don’t keep up on the new cell phone releases. To be clear, I am aware of big releases that have new features: I knew Motorola had a new phone that had removable addons, Samsungs are all(?) waterproof, and iPhones hadn’t really added much since the fingerprint reader.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fix HAXM Emulation Error in Android Studio</title><link>https://danthesalmon.com/posts/fix-haxm-emulation-error-in-android-studio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 04:57:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danthesalmon.com/posts/fix-haxm-emulation-error-in-android-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requirement Note:&lt;/strong> Android Studio requires an Intel processor with VT-X support for it’s built-in emulators to work. If you want to do Android development with emulators on an AMD processor, I would highly suggest using &lt;a href="https://www.genymotion.com/#!/">Genymotion&lt;/a>. If you’re not sure if your Intel processor supports VT-X, Intel has &lt;a href="http://www.intel.com/support/processors/sb/cs-030729.htm">an article here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This error is occurring because Android Studio requires Intel Hardware Accelerated Execution Manager (Intel HAXM) to run it’s emulators. All we need to do is install this tool.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>